# 嗨喽大家好
Hello,
# 今天我托我朋友弄了一些东西过来
Today, I asked my friends to send me something
# 四伯爷你晓得这是啥子不
Uncle, do you know what this is?
# 不晓得
I don’t know
# 这是叶子
These are leaves
# 你看嘛 新鲜的
Look, so fresh
# 就跟它那个大树上的拐爪儿（拐枣）差不多
It looks like Turn Jujube from the tree
# 这个是八角
This is star anise
# 你们有没有见过新鲜的八角
Have you seen fresh star anise before?
# 看到没 这个八角弄来晒一下
See, you air-dry this star anise
# 要晒好几天 把它晒干
For days, until it dries
# 2 4 6 8 嘿 八角还真是八个尖尖
Two, Four, Six, Eight. Star anise really has eight tips
# 只有8个 如果多几个出来的话那种就不是得
Only eight. If there is more, then it’s not star anise
# 那种有毒
It’s poisonous
# 这个有米米（籽）没得安
Does it have seeds?
# 有
Yes, it has
# 对了 它咋个种不起安
Oh, can the star anise be planted?
# 这边不好种 这个都烂了
It’s hard to plant it here. This one is rotten.
# 啥子不好种哦
How come?
# 前晚上我看那个新闻 人家种那个羊肚（菌）
I saw the news the other night. They planted the fungi culture
# 咋啦 用了好多钱哦
Spend a lot of money
# 始终人家最后还是干成功了的
They succeeded eventually
# 你闻哈看 四伯爷
Smell it, uncle
# 你这样掐了来闻
You break like this and smell it
# 就这样闻都闻得到 很香
I can smell like this, smells nice
# 掐一哈你再闻
Try to break it first and smell it
# 是不是很香
Doesn’t it smell nice?
# 嗯 很有好香
Eh, it smells nice
# 这个时候丢一颗（锅里）的话味道不晓得好大
If we throw one in the wok now, it’s going to smell great
# 因为以前我也没有见过这个新鲜的是什么样子
Because I have never seen star anise when it’s fresh
# 所以我托我朋友寄点过来
So I asked my friend to send some to me
# 也跟大家分享一下这个
And share with you all
# 我第一次看到八角像这个样子
It’s my first time seeing star anise like this
# 是不哦
Isn’t it so?
# 是啊
Yeah
# 长见识了噶
Learned new knowledge
# 这个呢就是叶子
This is the leaves
# 我朋友说这个产量最高的是在广西
My friend said Guangxi has the highest production of star anise
# 广西专门种这个的
Guangxi is specialized to grow star anise
# 这个弄来晒 晒一个星期左右
Air-dry it for about a week
# 35几天一个星期 晒干了来就可以用了
Three, five, a week. You can use it when it’s dried.
# 晒干了就放的久
The drier it is, the longer it can be stored
# 你数哈看嘛 随便拿一个来数哈
You count it, pick one
# 都是8个角角
All have eight tips
# 是 那这个就拿给你了 你晒一下晒了你用
Then this is yours. You use it after air-dried
# 因为有粉丝在问 老是问这个新鲜八角长什么样子
Because some fans ask, what does fresh star anise look like
# 今天给大家分享一下 就是长这个样子
I’m sharing with you today, it looks like this
# 绿色的 比较饱满
Green, plump
# 你们买的干的那种 它是缩起来的
The dry one you bought, it’s shrunken
# 就是这个已经被晒干了
After it’s air-dried
# 缩起来一片一片的
Shrunk into slides
# 一片一片的中间带了一个籽
Slides with seed in between
# 如果你们做菜的话最好就把那个籽去掉
When you are cooking, it’s better to remove the seed
# 好了本期视频就到这里了拜拜
Alright, that’s it for today, bye-bye